Taylor McClerin

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER · LinkedIn · Github

PROFILE: Public private, and third sector development professional. Recent graduate of App Academy with full stack capacity. Ten years of customer service experience, two years of managing in a for-profit environment, three years of international, non-profit experience managing direct services projects, and three years of public service experience. Strong leadership skills include training, task delegation, time management, and conflict resolution. Experienced in developing and executing M&E frameworks and applying results to program development for process improvement.

LANGUAGES:

JavaScript(JS), Python, Structured Query Language (SQL), Hypertext Markup Language (HTML), Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Git, R

FRAMEWORKS:

Sequelize, Express, SQLAlchemy, Flask, React, React-redux, Node.js

TOOLS:

Github, Amazon Web Services(AWS)

OTHER:

Statistical Product and Service Solutions (SPSS), Geographical Information Systems (GIS), Project coordination and management, Microsoft Office Software including Excel, French (advanced fluency) & Spanish (novice fluency)

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

SOIL MATES · Python · Flask · SQLAlchemy · React · Git · CSS · Mapbox

Github Repo· Live Site

- Employed Mapbox API with International Soil Research Information Center (ISRIC) API so users can click on a map to query soil data for that location, allowing for simple data retrieval without the need for knowing coordinates
- Implemented posting, commenting, and voting features which allow for users to share soil data and information similar to Stack Overflow
- · Utilized React Redux to manage state and normalize data, providing for smooth scaling into larger traffic and data sets
- · Implemented AWS functionality to provide user with optional profile picture and to allow them to customize their profile

EVERY NOTE · Python · Flask · SQLAlchemy · React · Git · CSS

Github Repo · Live Site

- Managed git pull requests and merge conflicts in group amicable group setting to create a clone of Ever Note in under two
 weeks
- Implemented Flask database backend and React front end to provide users with a note-taking function organized by notebooks and tags as well as a tasks keeper to reinforce user organization
- In combination with React-Redux store, organized components in a way to provide snappy response time to users with full CRUD functionality.

FAIR BNB · JS · Express · React · Git · CSS

<u>Github Repo</u> · <u>Live Site</u>

- Created clone of Airbnb with an emphasis on modal use as a means to expedite functionality
- Implemented Express backend with React-redux front end to provide quick response times for user
- Created rating system which dynamically responded to base calculations
- Employed AWS as a means for storing spot photos to provide longer-term data stability

RECENT EMPLOYMENT

VETERANS BENEFIT ADMINISTRATION (VBA) · Veterans Service Representative (VSR) · Chicago, IL

Sep 2019 - Aug 2022

- Served as the Homeless Veterans Claims Coordinator (HVCC), coordinating care and paperwork for homeless veterans to expedite benefit awards resulting in a 30-90% reduction in wait time
- Determined compensation eligibility by requesting, analyzing, and developing medical evidence
- Utilized various data processing systems to adjudicate, monitor, evaluate, and prepare correspondence
- Served as a primary contact for the veteran, advocating for disability benefits for them and their beneficiaries

GREENHEART EXCHANGE · Program Assistant · Chicago, IL

May - Aug 2019

- Directly and indirectly supported J-1 visa participants in navigating work, travel, and housing concerns by ensuring their health, welfare, and safety during their program
- Reviewed applications and vetted participant employers according to Department of State regulations
- Generated daily and weekly reports via database systems to support program management

PEACE CORPS (PC) TOGO Reforestation Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) Specialist · Togo, W. Africa

Jun 2015 - Sep 2018

• Managed cashew plantation projects by organizing community members, developing and constructing nurseries, collecting inputs (seed, manure, et cetera), maintaining and caring for seedlings, preparing sites, and organizing workdays. I organized community members to execute the planting of five (5) hectares of trees

- Trained and supervised a team of four Togolese and four PC Volunteers to conduct long term assessment of reforestation initiatives in rural Togo, conducted 41 site visits throughout the country, and generated a comprehensive outcomes report to redesign PC Togo's agroforestry program
- Wrote *Peace Corps Togo Reforestation Manual, 2018, pp 82*, with results-oriented reforestation techniques within a West African environmental and social context to improve reforestation, gender, and food security outcomes which has been distributed to each subsequent volunteer cohort since.
- Conducted comprehensive on-site needs assessment. In response trained, and coordinated a team of Togolese volunteers to cofacilitate 89 community trainings across five (5) villages for 663 adults and youth in reforestation, sustainable agriculture, nutrition, and environmental stewardship.
- Ensured volunteer acknowledgement and appreciation resulting in repeat participation in different events

TOD'S CAFÉ Assistant Manager (2012-2015).

- Managed bakery within a café that served 350 clients daily, grossing over \$300,000 annually
- Efficiently directed daily product delivery between sister restaurants, processed customers' special requests, and fulfilled catering orders
- Onboarded, trained, supervised, and managed staff meetings for five personnel
- Managed inventory, ordering, scheduling, and pricing to support senior management

EDUCATION

App Academy · Full Stack Web Development

Graduated July 2023

JS, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, SQLite3, Express, SQLAlchemy, Flask, React, Git, AWS, Node.js

DePaul University · Chicago, IL

Graduated August 2022

• Masters of Science in Public Policy

University of North Carolina Asheville · Asheville, NC

Graduated May 2013

- Bachelor of Science in Biology
- Bachelor of Arts in French